JERRY COMFORTER ASARE

Contact

Address:

Accra, Ghana.

Phone:

- +233 (0) 20 764 3293
- +233 (0) 54 694 2929

E-mail:

asarejerry16@gmail.com

GitHub:

@jcasare

LinkedIn:

jerry-asare-comforter

Website:

jerryasare.com

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science &

Engineering - 2020

University of Mines & Technology,

Tarkwa – Ghana.

Certifications

- AWS Solutions Architect Associate
- Agile Scrum Master
- Agile Scrum Professional
- Google Project Management Professional
- Google IT Support Professional Certificate
- Cisco Cyber Security Essentials
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Cisco Cyber Threat Management Certificate

Summary

Analytical, solutions-oriented Full Stack software development professional with experience driving complex, large-scale technical projects covering software/database, product implementation, and technical support. Expertise in Cloud DevOps and translating innovative ideas into technology solutions.

Highlights

- Project Management
- Customer Service
- Team-worker
- Service-focused

Skills

HTML, CSS (Bootstrap & Tailwind), Typescript, JavaScript (NodeJS, ExpressJS, NestJS, React.js, Vue.js, Alpine.js) PHP, Wordpress, MySQL & PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS, Git, Docker, Jenkins, RabbitMQ, Redis, Apollo GraphQL, Laravel, Jira, Prisma, TypeOrm, Jest, Prometheus, Grafana, Microservices, Websockets, API Management

Areas of Expertise

- UI/UX & Web Design
- Cloud DevOps
- Serverless

- Secure Systems
- Rest & Restful API
- AWS & GCP

Experience

Software Developer, GTN LLC - 07/2023 to Present

Transitioned a large Express.js backend for a leading US telco to a serverless
architecture using Nest.js and AWS Lambda, reducing API request run time
by 30%, lowering deployment costs by 70%, enhancing code security,
scalability, reliability, CI/CD processes,monitoring and logging.

Web Developer, WebSys Technology – 03/2023 to 12/2023.

 Designed and deployed 20+ responsive websites with SEO optimization, enhancing online visibility and engagement while driving company profit to a net-increase of 30%.

Web Developer, Freelance – 06/2021 to Present

Engineered bespoke client solutions, enhancing retention rates by 35% and driving a 30% increase in annual revenue through strategic implementation.

Web Developer, Kosans Royal – 02/2021 to 08/2023

 Built and optimized over 20 responsive websites with a focus on SEO, boosting online presence and user engagement, which resulted in a 30% rise in net profits.

IT Support, Telecel Ghana – 10/2020 to 06/2022.

 Provided tech-related support to Vodafone (now Telecel) customers including fibre broadband activations, mobile app support and others.